Guide to the Charles K. Field Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Charles K. Field collection
1895-1948
SC0575
Field, Charles K., (Charles Kellogg), 1873-1948.
18.25 Linear feet
This collection pertains largely to his connection with Stanford and includes the text of his talk on Stanford history, 1941 and 1945; text of his talk on the history of drama at Stanford in the 1890s, 1944; examples of his published songs and poetry; a Christmas letter to Jessie Knight Jordan (Mrs. David Starr Jordan), 1944; two photographs, 1896 and 1929; and biographical clippings.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Charles K. Field was a member of Stanford University's pioneer class, graduating in 1895 with an A.B. in English. He wrote many of the school's early songs and yells and, with Will Irwin, published STANFORD STORIES; his book of Stanford inspired poems, FOUR LEAVED CLOVER, was published in 1899. He pursued a career in journalism and radio, broadcasting on NBC for 15 years as "Cheerio."
Description of the Collection
This collection pertains largely to his connection with Stanford and includes the text of his talk on Stanford history, 1941 and 1945; text of his talk on the history of drama at Stanford in the 1890s, 1944; examples of his published songs and poetry; a Christmas letter to Jessie Knight Jordan (Mrs. David Starr Jordan), 1944; two photographs, 1896 and 1929; and biographical clippings.
Access Terms
Field, Charles K., (Charles Kellogg), 1873-1948.; College and school drama, American--California--Stanford.; Photoprints.
Collection Contents
- Papers (Box 1)
  - Charlie Field-day, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cheerio's favorite hymns, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clippings (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters and notes (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, 1896, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Published poetry (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Poem [typescript] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Stanford history talk, 1941, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Music manuscript, 1893? (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Two Stanford songs, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Stanford Red", 1895 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Music scores (commerical), Accession ARCH-2013-036
  - #1-67 (Box 1)
  - #38-67 (Box 2)
  - #68-100 (Box 3)
  - #101-150 (Box 4)
  - #151-211 (Box 5)
  - #212-294 (Box 6)
  - #295-490 (Box 7)
  - #491-931 (Box 8)
  - #932-1139 (Box 9)
  - Unfoldered (loose) Scores (Box 10-12)